# Adarsh Koppa Manjunath

Regina, SK S4S 2L1 | <u>adarshakmkmanjunath@gmail.com</u> | +16399993897 LinkedIn | GitHub| HackerRank

### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

I am a recent graduate in Master's in Computer Science from the University of Regina and have previously worked with Dell EMC as a Test Engineer. I have working experience in Automation Framework Development and Manual Testing, and Academic experience in Software Development, and Data Science.

## SKILL SUMMARY

- Around 5 years of Experience in Python Scripting and flexible with other OOP languages including C++, JAVA and C#.
- Strong experience in developing and maintaining Automation Framework for REST and CLI based interface.
- Experience in using Python based framework including Unittest, Selenium, Django and Kivy.
- Experience in handling and setting up the Jenkins server for the automation suite execution.
- Experience in defect management (JIRA) and Test Management (QMetry) tools.
- Experience in executing functional and non-functional testcases.
- Experience in using SSH tools including Putty and WinSCP.
- Experience in API testing using Automation Framework and Postman.
- Working experience in Agile Environment.
- Knowledge of Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Online courses and certifications in Python, Problem Solving, DevOps, Selenium, Docker, and REST API.
- Academic Experience in MySQL, Web Development using Design Patterns, MVT and UML concepts.
- Academic Experience in Machine Learning Model Development using Classification Algorithms and Transfer Learning techniques through NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, OpenCV, Keras and Scikit-learn.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Test Engineer - Dell EMC - Bengaluru, Karnataka

**July 2016 - December 2018** 

- Worked on a project called Skyline Chassis both as an Automation and a Manual Test engineer.
- Worked on Dell PowerEdge MX servers including chassis, compute sleds, storage sleds, and IO Modules.
- Contributed to a Data Driven Automation Framework development called NGM for the REST API testing.
- Developed and Maintained core modules and Testcases for Network, Device and Power based features.
- Used Python to develop HTML report generator, and report summary email notification tools.
- Developed required scripts for Stress, and Load Testing using Python.
- Developed basic stand-alone UI Automation scripts using Selenium and Java.
- Prepared and executed automation test suites using Jenkins for Build Verification and Regression Testing.
- Involved in Test Environment Setup which includes bringing up servers with the required configuration.
- Used QMetry to develop and execute test cases.
- Performed API, Integration, BlackBox, Compatibility, Security, Recovery, and Ad-hoc Testing.
- Used Postman for the REST API testing.
- Raised bugs and extensively used JIRA to manage the same.
- Worked in an Agile environment.

### Intern - Dell EMC - Bengaluru, Karnataka

February 2016 - May 2016

- Worked on a Project called REST API Automation
- Worked on Dell Remote Access Controller.
- Developed test cases using QMetry to compare RACADM and REST interfaces for Dell iDRAC server.
- Automated REST and RACADM interfaces using Dell Unit Framework.

## **EDUCATION**

## Master's in Computer Science - 83.3%

January 2019 - September 2020

University of Regina - Regina, SK

Courses- Software Development, Data Science, Image Processing, and Computer Networking related fields.

#### **Bachelor's in Information Science-72.65%**

**September 2012 - July 2016** 

UVCE - Bangalore Urban, Karnataka

Courses- Programming Languages (C, C++, Java, PHP and C#), Data Structures and Algorithms, OOPs, Database systems, Data Mining, Networking, Computer Architecture, Web Development, Neural Networks, and WSN.

# RELEVANT ACADEMIC PROJECTS

## **Improved Search Engine - Source Code**

**January 2020 – April 2020** 

- Developed Search Engine using Threading and Sentiment Analysis techniques.
- Used MVT architecture with the help of Django.
- Integrated Design Patterns like Proxy, Observer, and Factory.
- Used SQLite for the database.
- Deployed using GitHub and Heroku.
- Followed all coding standards including logging, documentation, error handling, naming conventions etc.
- Developed Technical documentation using UML- Usecase, Class, Activity, Component, and Deployment.

### **Produce Item Recognition-Source Code**

**January 2020 – April 2020** 

- Developed an application for produce item recognition using Machine Learning Techniques.
- Developed Fruits and Vegetables Dataset of Size 3GB.
- Used Machine Learning Models like CNN, VGG16, and Resnet 50.
- Used Evaluation Metrics like Classification Report and Confusion Matrix.
- Developed an Application to operationalize using the Kivy Python framework.
- Developed technical documentation, setup, and user guidelines.

#### **Art Gallery of Regina**

November 2019- December 2019

- Found the existing issues and opportunities to redesign.
- A created a mental model, low level, and high-level designs.
- The new design was done by considering the 10 Usability Heuristics for User Interface Design.
- Performed usability and acceptance testing.

## **IMDB Sentimental Analysis – Source Code**

November 2019- December 2019

- Used NLP, Porter Stemming, Regular Expressions, Counter Vectorization, and TFIDF for preprocessing
- Used SVM, Logistic Regression and Naive Bayes to develop machine learning model.

# Online Certifications - See Certificates

- Certified in Python (Advanced), Problem Solving, and REST API from Hacker Rank.
- Certified in Docker Fundamentals from Kode Kloud.
- Completed Python 3 Programming assessment from IKM with 95%.

# **Additional Information**

- Languages- English, Kannada, and Hindi.
- Visa Status- PGWP (Can work for any employer)
- Relocation- Willing to relocate anywhere in Canada.